<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cryptographies on The Security Dōjō</title><link>http://example.org/cryptography/</link><description>Recent content in Cryptographies on The Security Dōjō</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 13:33:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AES Basics</title><link>http://example.org/cryptography/aes_basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 13:33:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/cryptography/aes_basics/</guid><description>AES-ECB Electronic Code Book (ECB) is a simple block cipher. Given a plaintext block P it will produce a ciphertext block C. Meaning, if you have multiple identical plaintext blocks, AES-ECB will produce identical ciphertext blocks. Because of this property, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to encrypt information longer than BLOCK_SIZE because any repeating blocks will produce identical ciphertext blocks. This leaks information about the plaintext which is considered insecure.
Encryption Decryption AES-CBC Cipher block chaining (CBC) mode is one of the more common modes used in AES.</description></item><item><title>AES Padding Oracle I</title><link>http://example.org/cryptography/aes_padding_oracle_i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 13:33:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/cryptography/aes_padding_oracle_i/</guid><description>When using AES in CBC mode without any integrity checks such as a MAC, it can be possible to leak information about a ciphertext which can lead to full plaintext recovery. Under such circumstances the attacker is able to send arbitrary ciphertexts to be decrypted to an oracle (e.g. application service) and obtain the result of the decryption. If the result indicates that a padding error has occurred, the attacker can use the information to recover the plaintext without knowing the secret key.</description></item><item><title>AES Padding Oracle II</title><link>http://example.org/cryptography/aes_padding_oracle_ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 13:33:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/cryptography/aes_padding_oracle_ii/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s modify ciphertexts!</description></item></channel></rss>